ERVINS ZAGARS

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

Email: ervins.zagars@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://ervinszagars.com/
LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/30DZL3R
GitHub: https://github.com/ErvinsZ/

A coder who is currently specializing in React, but open to learning new frameworks. Has also acquired understanding of backend operations through building full MERN stack applications. Before worked in sales as a sales agent and later on as a team lead in the same company

TECH SKILLS:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB

SOFT SKILLS:

Team work, Task prioritization, Constructive feedback

EDUCATION

Strive School 04.2020 - 10.2020

MERN STACK

- MongoDB, ExpressJs, React, NodeJs
- Got also introduced to relational databases, specifically PostgreSQL

Swansea University 2014-2017

BS Criminology and Criminal Justice

- Cybercrime: Deviance, Crime and Terror
- Terrorism and the Global Response
- Biological, Psychological and Social Crime Theories

EXPERIENCE

International Travel Network 2017-2020

Sales agent 2018-2019

- Tremendously improved communication skills by performing over the phone sales
- Got promoted to work with business class clients after nine months of being in the company

Sales Team Lead 2019-2020

- Took over an existing team consisting of individuals from many different countries and diverse backgrounds
- Improved interpersonal relationships within the team through team building activities
- Increased profits produced by the team by 40%

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS:

CryptoVisualizer (JS, React)

Code: https://bit.ly/2STZ3vb

- Worked with two third party API's (cryptocompare.com.highcharts.com)
- Dynamically displayed information of user selected crypto currency on a graph.
- Used CSS Grid and styled-components library



WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS:

Linkedin Clone (MERN Full Stack App)

Code: https://bit.ly/2SWT88v

- Acquired understanding of full-stack development and how front-end, back-end are connected together
- Experience gained working in a team by following SCRUM principles
- Created REST API routes for user profiles using NodeJs

Spotify Mockup (HTML, CSS)

Code: https://bit.ly/3nReDWt

- Created responsive design to fill all screen sizes
- Interface built using Bootstrap library